The following is dedicated to everyone out there
gathered together once again to enjoy this precious world
and the companionship of their dear old friends...
498 years ago
Why is it that humans destroy...
破壊と創造
人間はどうして繰り返すんだろうね
...only to rebuild over and over again?
I just can't understand it.
僕には理解出来ないよ
That's because humans are terrible at remembering things.
人間は思い出というものが苦手なのさ
They alter them, embellish them,
だから美化し 拡大する
replacing painful memories with nostalgic ones,
痛みは懐かしさに変えて
過去を乗り越えようとする
all in an effort to rise above their past.
So you're saying that's the reason why...
母さんを取り戻そうとしたのも
...they tried to bring Mother back?
思い出のせい ?
It was an effort to escape the harshness of reality.
それは現状の困難を取り除くためだ
星痕のことを言つてるのかい ?
What, the Geostigma?
でも元はと言えば あんたたちのせいだ
If we're pointing fingers, then it was you humans who started this whole mess.
そうか
Oh, I get it...
あんたもやっぱり思い出が苦手なんだ
Your memory's just as "convenient" as the rest of theirs...
No, I...
いや 私は--
...just happen to have the mind of a sieve.
実に忘れっぽい
2 weeks earlier
ツォンさん!
Tseng-san!
Look at this!
見てください!
Seems like we guessed right.
当たりだ
This makes me feel sick.
・・・気持ち悪いっすね
いいから急げよ　と
It's fine. Just hurry, okay?
Reno, do it.
レノ たのむ
Okay.
はいよ　と
Hey! Hey! Hey!
おいおいおい！
先輩 早く!
Senpai, hurry up!
先輩!
Senpai!
Huh? Who's there?
あれ　誰だ!?
うつ
イリーナ！
Elena!
い　行って！
R-Run away...
Tseng-san!
ツォンさん!
Lifestream...
ライフストリーム
The flow of life that traverses the planet.
それは星を巡る命の流れ
It is the source of life for the planet, and all things that live on it.
星と 星に生きる全ての命の源です
神羅カンパニーはライフストリームを
Shinra Company found a way to use the Lifestream as an energy resource.
資源として使う方法を見つけました
そのおかげで 私たちの生活は
As a result, our standards of living greatly improved.
とても豊かになりました
でも それは 星の命を削ること
But isn't it sucking away the life of the planet?
Many people agree with this opinion.
そう考える人も大勢いました
神羅は自分たちに反対する人々を
Shinra started using force to suppress those who disagreed with them.
力で抑えようとしました
So they created special troops called SOLDIER.
神羅には ソルジャ一という
特別な兵士たちがいました
A long time ago, a calamity fell from the skies...
大昔に 空から降ってきて
...and almost destroyed the planet.
この星を滅ぼ'そうとした災厄
ジェノバの細胞を埋めこんだ人たちです
It was called Jenova and SOLDIERs were infused with her cells.
Among these SOLDIERs, there was a man called Sephiroth.
その中にセフィロスという
An exceptional soldier.
とても優秀なソルジャーがいました
But once he found out that he was only a sample from a dreadful experiment,
でも 自分が 恐ろしい実験で
生まれたことを知って
he began to hate Shinra.
神羅を'憎むようになりました
And eventually, he started to hate everything else.
そして いつしか 全てを
憎むようになってしまいました
Shinra... and the people who opposed Shinra.
神羅と神羅に反対する人たち
Sephiroth's overflowing hatred caused him to attempt to destroy the planet.
憎しみのあまり 星を破壊して
しまおうとするセフィ囗ス
The people who were trying to stop Sephiroth,
セフィロスを止めようとする人たち
いくつもの戦いがありました
had many battles with him.
The more battles they had, the more tragedy they created.
戦いの数だけ悲しみがありました
And a person I loved became part of the Lifestream as well.
私が大好きだった人も
ライフス卜リ一ムになってしまいました
And, on that day...
そして あの日
the day of destiny,
運命の日
it was the power of the planet itself which ended all the battles.
すベての戦いを終わらせたのは
星自身の力でした
The planet used the Lifestream as a weapon...
星はライフストリ一ムを
武器として使いました
...and when it burst out of the ground...
地上に吹き出したライスとリームは
...all the fighting, all the greed and sorrow...
争い　野望　悲しみ
...everything was washed away.
全てを飲み込んでしまいました
"Sadness was the price to see it end."
悲しみと引きかえに 全部終わったんだよ
That's what I was told two years ago.
そう言われたのは 2年前でした
ねえ 行こう
Let's go.
Yeah.
うん
うわあ 危ねえな
Hey! Careful!
でも・・・星は
But it seems the planet...
...was far angrier than we imagined...
わたしたちが思うより ずっとずっと
怒っているみたいです
Geostigma Syndrome.
(セイコンショウコウグン)
星痕症候群
なあ マリン?
Hey, Marlene.
What's wrong with me?
どうなってる?
お願いです
Please.
Please, don't take Denzel away.
どうかデンゼルを
連れて行かないでください
According to the latest data published by the Board of Investigation,
今朝発表された
調査委員会の報告によれば
the Lifestream concentration of our atmosphere is at an all-time low,
nearly 0.01% of what is was 2 years ago.
大気中のライフストリーム濃度は
2年前の100分の1 程度で
That's a level so low, it has absolutely no effect on the human body.
人体にまったく影響の無いレベルまで
下がっているとのことです
However, as for the Shinra Company's corporate headquarters...
しかし神羅カンパ二ー本社ビル・・・
He's not here anymore.
もうここにはいないんですよー
...as well as the area surrounding its Mako reactors...
・・・依然 危険レベルにあり
Lifestream readings remain dangerously high.
In order to prevent the spread of Geostigma,
the Board has issued an official warning...
星痕発症を避けるために
該当施設周辺には
...not to go anywhere near the building or its neighboring facilities.
近づかないようにと
委員会は警告しています
Next up, we have news pertaining to developments in the pending lawsuits
filed against the Shinra Company...
次は神羅カンパ二ーに対する
補償請求に関する二ュースです
Cloud...
クラウド・・・
どこにいるんだよ・・・
Where are you?
Hello, this is Strife Delivery Service.
はい ス卜ライフ・デリバリー・サービスです
当社は なんでも・ ・ ・
Anything you want delivered, we...
Who is this?
・・・どちらさまですか?
覚えてるぞ と
Of course, I remember.
Reno made a call from Healen.
ヒーリンにいるレノから電話あったよ
仕事の依頼だって
He says he's got work for you.
クラウド・・・元気にしてるの?
Cloud, how have you been?
You have no more messages.
メッセージは以上です
So, Kadaj... Is that Big Brother's city?
なあ 力ダ'ージユあれが兄さんの街か ?
Yeah.
ああ
歓迎してくれると思うか?
Do you think he'll welcome us?
無理無理
Never ever.
Don't cry, Yazoo.
泣くなよ ヤズー
母さんもー緒なんだよな ?
Mother should be with him, right?
Who knows...
どうかな
泣くなよ ロッズ
Don't cry, Loz.
Look, it's our big brother.
ほら 兄さんだ
Where is Mother?
母さんはどこだ?
兄さんが隠してるんだろ ?
Did you hide her?
もしかして 僕をだました ?
Did you trick me, perhaps?
やっぱり母さんはそっちなんだろ?
Mother should be with you, right?
Don't yell.
怒鳴るなよ
あんたとは話したくない
I don't want to talk to you.
Put the President on.
社長に代わって
You wouldn't abandon us, right?
逃げたんじやないよね?
Hey, it's Barret!
おう バレットだ! オレはやったぞ!
新しい油田だ!
I did it! I found a new oil field!
ゆ で ん! すげえでかいやつだ
An o-i-l-f-i-e-l-d! And it's huge!
でな めどが付いたんで もうすぐマリンに会いに行くからな！
I've got my claim staked out, so I'll be heading to see Marlene soon!
Tell her for me! Later!
伝えとけよ じゃあな
Reno called again.
レノからまた雷話です
He said we have to hurry up.
とにかく急いでくれ だって
He sounded kind of strange.
なんだか様子が変だったけど
・ ・ ・気をつけてね
Be careful, okay?
うぉりや~~
さすがだぞ と
Not bad, dude.
ルード！　カッコいい！
Hey, Rude. Looking cool.
As expected from the ex would-be SOLDIER.
さすがだ 自称元ソルジャー
腕は鈍っていないようだな
You haven't rusted a bit.
Is that you, Rufus?
ルーファスナのか？
あんたもついていないな
Seems like you weren't lucky either.
あの日 私は・・・
That day, I managed to make it out somehow...
俺に何の用だ?
Why were you looking for me?
Just before the building collapsed.
ビルが崩れ落ちる直前に・ ・ ・
俺を襲った奴らは ?
Who are those guys that attacked me?
なんとか
I'm going!
帰るぞ
・・・おまえの力を借してくれ
I'd like you to help me.
興味ないね
Not interested...
We, the Shinra company, owe a huge debt to the rest of the world.
我ら神羅カンパ二ーは世界に対して大きな借りがある
There's no getting around the fact...
世界をこのようなみじめな状態にした貢任は
我々にあると言われても仕方がない
...that we are responsible for dragging the world into this pitiful state.
Therefore, we must work to undo the damage we have done.
よって この負債はなんとしても
返さねルまならないのだ
Open up, man!
開けてくれよ
As a first step towards this,
その第一歩として
我々はセフィ囗スが残した
影響の調査を始めた
we began investigating the influence Sephiroth left behind.
It's been two years since then.
あれから２年
復興の道を歩み出した世界の一番の脅威は何だ?
And what do you suppose has been
the greatest threat to our efforts to rebuild our world?
That's right...
そう 忌まわしき星痕症候群だ
The dreaded Geostigma Syndrome.
我々はその原因がセフィ囗スにあると考えている
We believe that this disease stems from Sephiroth.
The rest of the world believes Mako Reactors, Mako Energy...
Note: Mako is a condensed form of life-energy found on the planet as a liquid,
which flows en-masse inside the planet as the Lifestream.
世間では魔胱炉や魔胱工ネルギー
そしてライフス卜リームが星痕の原因だと考えられている
...and the Lifestream itself to be the ultimate cause.
But is that really so?
しかし本当にそうだろうか
The Lifestream came into existence along with our planet,
ライフストリームは星の誕生とともにあり
and Mako Energy has been in use for well over 40 years.
魔胱工ネルギーがヾ実用化されてから40年以上だ
Despite these facts...
にもかかわらずー
The Geostigma is nowhere to be found in historical records.
星痕などー度も歴史[こ登場しない
では
So...
What could have possibly happened to cause it in our time?
我々の時代に　いったい何が起こったというのだ?
There is only one answer...
考えられることはひとつ
セフィロスの登場だ
The birth of Sephiroth.
セフィロスは死んだ
Sephiroth is dead!
やつの精神はどうだ ?
But what of his consciousness?
Sure, his body dissolved into the Lifestream...
ライフストリームに溶け
But what if, instead of being scattered,
his consciousness as a whole now traverses the planet?
しかし拡散することなく
星を巡っているとしたら?
もちろん これは私の想像だ
Of course, this is mere speculation.
But we cannot disregard the possibility.
しかし可能性は捨てきれない
真実を知ることが
星痕の治療いも繋がる
Uncovering the truth about this disease will direct us to its cure.
Thus, for that reason...
そこで我々はー
...we began searching for Sephiroth's legacy.
セフィロスの痕跡の調査を始めた
まずは・・・
The first place was...
覚えているか ?
Take a guess.
The Northern Crater, dude.
北の大空洞だぞ と
What do you think we found?
何があったと思う？
Relax...
安心しろ
We found nothing.
あそこには何もなかった
However, something unexpected happened.
しかし 予期せぬことが起こった
奴らが・・・
We encountered... them.
現れたのだ
G-Go!
い　行って！
Kadaj and his gang.
カダ一ジユのー味だ
Kadaj...
カダ一ジユ・・・
奴はおまえも狙ってくるぞ
...is certain to target you as well.
もう接触があったのではないか？
Or perhaps I should say, you two are already well acquainted?
俺Lま関係ない
I'm not involved in this.
必ず返してもらうからね
We're coming for her!
No...
いや
You, like us, are someone who was deeply involved with Sephiroth.
おまえも我々同様
セフィ囗スと深く関わった者
If Kadaj is truly taking steps in preparation of that inevitable day,
カダ一ジユの目的が やがて来る
その瞬間の準備だとしたら・・・
there isn't anyone else out there who can stand up to his group like we can.
我々ほど邪魔な存在はないだろう
Preparations for what?
準備?
セフィ囗ス・・・
Sephiroth's...
...revival.
復活
話は終わりか？
Can I go now?
では本題に入る
I'll cut to the chase.
We need your power to stand up to Kadaj and his men.
カダ一ジユたちに対抗するには
おまえの力が必要なのだ
Won't you lend us a hand? Ex-SOLDIER, Cloud...
手を組まないか？
元ソルジャ一・クラウド
自称な
You mean, would-be.
What did they mean by "Mother"?
母さんって何のことだ?
さあ
Who knows...
Did Kadaj say something?
力ダ一ジュが何か言ったのか?
Rufus...
ルーファウス
何を隠している?
What is it you're hiding?
I wouldn't hide anything from someone willing to fight on our side.
ともに戦う同志に
隠し事などしなに
I know you're searching for information about the Geostigma, just like me.
おまえも星痕の情報は
欲しいはずだ
一緒に暮らす孤児たちのために
But you do it for the orphans you've taken in.
Don't you want to return the smiles to their faces?
子供たちに笑顔を取り戻して
やりたくはないか？
我々の最終目的は
世界の再建だ クラウド
All we want to do is bring this world back to life, Cloud.
俺は・・・
I...
Come on, Cloud. It's for Shinra Company's resurrection, dude.
頼む クラウド
神羅カンパ二ーの再建だぞ と
I'm not interested.
興味ないね
Reno!
レノ!
Does Cloud live here?
クラウドはここに住んでるの ?
Seems like it.
そうみたいだね
What's this?
何?
Just like Denzel's.
デンゼルと同じ!
クラウドも病気なの! ?
Is Cloud sick too?
He should have told me.
言ってくれればいいのに
病気だだら出ていったの？
Did he leave because he was sick?
I think he wants to fight it alone.
ひとりで戦う気なんだよ
戦う?
Fight?
No...
ちがう・ ・ ・
He doesn't want to fight at all.
戦う気なんかないんだ
ティファ?
Tifa?
帰ろう　マリン
Let's go back, Marlene.
No! I want to see Cloud!
やだ クラウドに会いたい
・・・そうだね
Yeah...
You really want to see him, don't you?
会いたいよね
Yeah!
うん!
Say, what should we do when we see him?
ねえ 会ったらどうしようか?
一緒に帰る !
We'll go home together!
Before that, we owe him a little lecture, don't we?
その前にお説教だね
Agreed!
賛成!
Now all that's left is the search for Elena and the chief!
後は主任とイリーナの捜索だな
Any news from the other employees?
他の社員からの情報は?
None as of this moment.
今のところは
Gotta say, more of the old bunch is getting back together than I expected.
元社員・・・ 思ってたより
集まって来てるよな
I'm getting pumped!
オレ 感動したぜ
We'll be able to recover the company in no time!
これなら やり なおせるぞ って
It's our duty as survivors to atone for what's happened.
償いは 生き残った者の使命だ
あれからもう2年
It's already been two years since then...
ん?
Only... two years?
まだ 2年か?
ありゃ悪夢だった
Well, it sure was a nightmare.
I thought the world was going to be destroyed...
世界が無くなるところだったんだ
...all because of our company.
俺ら神羅のせいでよ
Being serious for a second here,
真面目な話
exactly how much will it take to atone for our mistakes?
どんだけ償えばえいいだろうな
We really need to get the chief back...
やっぱり 主任がいてくれないとなぁ
...and Elena.
イリーナも
生きててくれよ・ ・・
I hope you're alive, guys.
大丈夫
Not to worry.
Tseng-san, like the President,
ツォンさんも社長と同じ
was nearly one foot in the grave before.
一度死にかけた
悪運は強い
But he's got the devil's luck!
Yeah, you said it!
だよな~ !
見つけた・ ・ ・
Found you.
教会って？
The church?
ああ　あそこのか
Ah, you're over there?
うん 待ってる
Yeah, I'll wait.
I'm sorry, the number you're trying to reach
in Sector 7 has been disconnected. Please try another number.
七番街の電話は全て不通となっています
I'm sorry, the number you're trying to reach
in Sector 7 has been disconnected. Please try another number.
七番街の電話は全て不通となっています
I'm sorry, the number you're trying to reach
in Sector 7 has been disconnected. Please try another number.
七番街の電話は全て不通となっています
I'm sorry, the number you're trying to reach
in Sector 7 has been disconnected. Please try another number.
七番街の電話は全て不通となっています
I'm sorry, the number you're trying to reach
in Sector 7 has been disconnected. Please try another number.
七番街の電話は全て不通となっています
Cloud?
クラウド
It's rare that I get a call from you.
電話してくるなんてめずらしいのね
Something up?
何かった？
Cloud?
クラウド?
It's not.
違うんです
誰?
それ クラウドの電話でしよ ?
Who is this? You're using Cloud's cell, right?
わかりません
I don't know!
Who is this?
誰なの ?
わかりません
I don't know!
僕 どうしたらいいのかわからないんです
I don't know... what I'm supposed to do!
Are you... crying?
きみ ないてるの？
どうしたの? 大丈夫?
What's happening?! Are you okay?!
Cloud? Cloud! Are you there?!
クラウド! クラウド!
そこにいるの？
おい!
Hey!
大丈夫か ?
Are you all right?
I hate lies!
ウソは嫌いだな
悪かった 今度こそ正直に言おう
My apologies. I'll be honest this time.
あれは おまえたちから逃げる途中
It seems it fell from the helicopter while we were running from you.
ヘリから落としたらしい
間の抜けた話だ
Sounds silly, isn't it?
本当に ?
Is that true?
誓って
I swear.
じゃ これに誓ってよ
Then swear on these.
目的は・・・何だ?
What is it you want?
母さんの力が必要なんだよ
We need Mother's power.
リユ二オンには どうしても
It's absolutely necessary for Reunion.
Reunion?
リユ二オン・・・
母さんの細胞をもらった仲間が１か所に集まるんだ
All those infused with Mother's cells will gather in one place.
Then we are all going to take revenge on this planet!
そして星に復讐するんだよ
準備は着々と進んでいるけど
Preparations are progressing smoothly so far, but...
You see, a certain someone has hidden Mother...
ほら 誰かさんが母さんを隠しちやったからさ
準備だと ?
Preparations, you say?
Geost...
星痕
Well, you know of it already, don't you, President?
社長もよく知ってるよね
It's all thanks to the efforts of Mother's genes inside the Lifestream.
ライフストリームの中で
母さんの遺伝思念が頑張ってるおかげなんだ
それなのに僕たちは
But we...
母さんの居場所すら知らない
We don't even know where Mother is.
情けないけど　仕方がないんだよ
It's pathetic, but we can't help it!
僕たちは思念体だからさ
We're just Remnants, after all.
母さんを見つけて
細胞を分けてもらうまで
Until we find Mother and take in some of her cells,
元通りにはなれない
we can't be whole again.
思念と星痕だけじや足リなんだ
Geostigma and a legacy aren't enough.
本当のリユ二オンにはね
Not for a true Reunion.
What are you talking about?
・・・何の話だ?
President...
社長・・・気づいているんだろ？
You've noticed, haven't you?
Whoops, my bad!
ごめんごめん
うわ! 星痕!
Ah! Geostigma!
Go home and don't come out here again!
家から出るなよな !
You dropped this...
これ・・・
"I will live for you, as well."
おまえの分まで生きよう
You know that's what I'd decided...
そう決めたんだけどな・ ・ ・
ソルジヤーになりたいって?　頑張れよ！
So you want to be a SOLDIER? Good luck!
Hey! How do you feel?
おい 気分はどうだ?
なあ ミグ ミッドガルに着いたら
おまえ どうする?
Say, when we get to Midgar, what are you going to do?
We're friends, right?
卜モダチ だろ?
おっさん!
どこか岩陰で止めてくれ!
Pops! Get us behind the rocks!
Cloud, we're getting off!
クラウド 降りるぞ!
俺の誇りや夢
My pride, my dream...
They're both yours now...
全部やる
...because you're...
おまえがー
...the proof that I existed.
俺の生きた証
Back then, I swore I'd never forget.
あの時 忘れないと誓つた
But...
でもー
俺は・・・
I...
悲しむふりはやめろ
Stop pretending to mourn.
Nor is there any need for this fabricated fit of anger.
怒りに震える演技も必要ない
Because, Cloud...
なぜなら クラウド
You are...
おまえはー
...a puppet.
人形だ
あ!
Wanna play?
遊ぼうか
I see. You don't want to, huh?
そうか　いやか
Where's Mother?
母さんは?
あ?
くせえ
It stinks!
なあ　母さんは?
Hey, where's Mother?
誰もいないわよ !
There's no one here!
じゃあ 遊ぼう
Well, then... Let's play.
こりや楽しみだ
This will be fun.
ティフア!
Tifa!
ここじゃねえな
Looks like it ain't here.
泣いてねえよ
I'm not crying!
わかった
Fine.
連れてく
I'll bring her with me.
続きだ
Let's continue.
Cloud!
クラウド・・・
Run!
逃げて !
I'm sorry... about earlier.
さっきは　ごめん
Thanks.
ありがとう
うん
It's okay.
My little brother...
弟・・・
...is gone.
もういないんだ
そっか・・・
Oh.
ねえ きみも星痕だよね?
You've got Geostigma too, don't you?
They're saying they can cure it!
治してくれるんだって
Tifa?!
ティファ？
Tifa!
ティファ!!
遅いよ・ ・ ・
You're late...
Who did this?
誰がやった？
I don't know who he was.
知らない奴
Marlene!
マリン! ?
くそっ !
Damn!
重かったぞ　と
You were heavy, man.
・・・あんた 子供たちと住んでいたよな
You were living with a bunch of kids, right?
That place is empty.
空っぽだ
いいのか？
Are you okay with that?
俺は・・・
I...
じれったいぞ　と
You really get on my nerves, dude.
Tifa said to pick you up.
ティファがおまえを連れて来いと言っている
つかまれ
Grab on tight.
So who's this person that can cure us?
誰が治してくれるの ?
わかんない
Dunno.
うん・・・ もう・・・ 誰だっていいや
Yeah... It doesn't matter who, anyway.
So Brother was hiding these...
兄さんが隠してたのか・・・
Power born from the Lifestream.
ライフストリームから生まれた力
このマテリ アで僕たちも新たな力を・・・
And now this Materia will grant us new power.
Is that... something Mother left behind for us?
それ 母さんが残してくれたんだろ?
ああ きっと
Yes, I'm sure.
母さんも兄さんが隠してるのか?
Are you hiding Mother from us too, Brother?
いや あの社長だ
No, no... That President is.
神羅カンパ二ーは昔から母さんを隠すのが好きなんだ
He and his Shinra Company have always had fun hiding Mother from us.
Guess that means we gotta search
every single place related to Shinra inside-out, then?
じゃあ 神羅に関係のある場所を片っ端から探せばいいな
うん もうすぐ仲間が大勢増える
Yes... but we'll soon be getting a lot more help!
I can't wait!
楽しみだなあ
その前に・・・
But before that...
兄さんに文句を言わなくちゃ
I have a bone to pick with you, Brother.
You act like you're not a part of this family...
全部自分には関係ないって顔して・ ・・
...and that makes me feel all alone.
寂しいよ ホントニ
わあ!
きゃあ!
Can't you see?
ねえ?
レノたちが探している
Reno and the others are looking for them now.
星痕症候群・ ・ ・だよね
You have Geostigma, don't you?
So it's okay to just give up and die. Is that what you think?
このまま死んでもいい
・・・なんて思ってる?
Just as I thought.
やっぱり
治療法がない
There is no cure for it.
でも デンゼルは頑張ってるよね
That's not stopping Denzel from fighting.
逃げないで 一緒に闘わない ?
Don't run from it. Let's fight together!
Let's help each other out, try our best!
みんなで助け合って頑張ろうよ
本当の家族じゃないから　ダメか
But since we're not a real family... I guess not, huh?
俺には
I don't think...
誰も助けられないと思うんだ
...that I can save anybody.
Family... or friends.
家族だろうが　仲間だろうが・ ・ ・
No one.
誰も
ズルズルズルズル
Drag, drag...
ズルズルズルズル !
Drag, drag.
いつまで引きずってるんだ　と
How long are you going to keep dragging it along with you?
見つからないの？
You couldn't find them?
There's someone who saw where they were taken to.
奴らが連れて行った
目撃者がいたぞ　と
Where?
行き先は ?
The Forgotten City.
忘らるる都
アジ卜だ
It's their base.
僕は母さんから特別な力を授がつた
I have a special power bestowed upon me by Mother.
The power to fight...
人間を苦しめる
...against the planet that torments its people.
この星と闘うための力だ
Actually, all of you have this power.
実は この力はみんなも持つている
そう
That's right.
僕たちは兄弟なんだ
We are all brothers and sisters.
We have inherited Mother's genetic remnants,
which are infused within the Lifestream.
ライフストリームに溶けていた
母さんの遺伝思念を受け継いだ
選Lまれし兄弟
However,
でも
星がみんなの邪魔を している
the planet is stopping us!
It's trying to prevent our growth.
僕たちの成長を止めてしまおうとしている
That's why your body aches and your heart feels crushed.
だから君たちの身体は痛み
心が挫けそういなるんだ
治してあげ'るよ
Allow me to cure you all.
Then we will return to Mother.
そして母さんのところヘ行こう
Let's unite our strength and take revenge on this planet.
家族で力を合わせて
星に仕返しするんだ!
Follow me.
僕に続づいて
デンゼル！
Denzel...
デンゼル! !
Denzel!
Mother, are you watching?
母さん 見て
Look at all the brothers and sisters I've made!
こんなに兄弟が増えたんだ
Now, I won't be lonely anymore...
これで母さんに会えるまで
...while I'm waiting to see you again.
僕は寂しくないよ
来ちゃったね
You came.
自分が壊れそうなのに ね
Even though you're about to fall apart, right?
きっと　いいことだよ
It's probably a good sign.
質問
Question!
どうして来たのかな ?
Why did you come?
俺は・・・許されたいんだと思う
I... think I want to be forgiven.
うん 俺は許されたい
Yes, I want to be forgiven.
誰に~?
By whom?
やっぱり来たね
I knew you'd come!
子供たちを迎えに来た
I am here to take the children back.
This man here... He's our big brother!
この人はね 僕たちの兄さんだ
でもね 残念だけど
However,
unfortunately,
裏切り者なんだよ
he is a traitor.
クラウド!
Cloud!
本当に・ ・ ・誰も助けられないな
I really can't save anyone.
Vincent, what's going on?
ヴィンセン卜・・・
何が起こってるんだ?
I come here often.
私はここによく来る
だからカダ一ジユたちのことは見ていた
That's why I've been watching Kadaj and his gang.
星痕は
Geostigma...
体内に巣食った異物を排除するシステムの過剰な働きが原因らしい
...seems to be caused by an overworked system
trying to remove foreign cells from your body.
身体の中にもライフストリームにのような流れがあり
There is a flow inside our bodies similar to the Lifestream...
それが親友してきた
邪悪な物質と闘うわけだ
...and that stream fights evil substances that have invaded our body.
Evil substances...
邪悪な物質・ ・ ・
The Sephiroth mark. Jenova's genes.
セフィ囗ス因子
ジェノバの遺伝思念
好きに呼べ
Call it what you like.
You sure know a lot.
詳しいな
ツォンとイリーナ
Tseng and Elena.
死にかけての状態でここヘ運ばれてきた
They were brought here half-dead.
It looked like they'd been heavily tortured.
ずいぶん醜い拷問を受けたようだ
助けてはやったが・・・
I did help them, but...
ふん　どうだろうな
I don't know.
Torture?
拷問?
自業自得
They had it coming.
It seems they got their hands on Jenova's head.
ジェノバの首を手に入れたらしい
Then the mother Kadaj is looking for...
力ダ一ジュが探している
母親というのは・ ・・
The accursed being sent by heaven,
天が送りし 忌まわしき者
Jenova.
ジェノバ
If they want to, they can make another Sephiroth.
その気になれば再びセフィ囗スを作りJ出すことができる
Kadaj...
カダ一ジュ・・・
何者だ
Who is he anyway?
ふん　かんがえたくもない
I don't even want to think about it.
マリン！
Marlene!
Cloud! Denzel and Tifa...
クラウド！デンゼルが！デンゼルが！
Tifa is fine.
ティファは大丈夫だ
I want to talk to Tifa.
ティファと話したい!
持ってる?
Do you have one?
信じられない !
Unbelievable...
ヴィンセン卜 マリンを店ヘ送つてくれないか?
Vincent, can you take Marlene back?
俺は神羅の連中の話を聞きに行く
I'm going to ask those Shinra guys some questions...
賛成しがねる
I can't agree with that plan.
But...
でも・・・
クラウドはもういい!
Cloud, I've had enough.
どうしてあたしたちの話は聞いてくれないの?
Why won't you listen to us?
マリン
Marlene...
もう少し待ってくれ
Give me a bit more time.
A battle will start soon.
これから戦いが始まるはずだ
でも ただ戦えばいいわけじゃない
But... only fighting is not enough.
わかるよな？
Do you understand?
わかりません！
No, I don't.
クラウド・ ・ ・これは戦いの話か?
Cloud, are you talking about fighting again?
行き先は ?
Where?
The Forgotten City.
忘らるる都
アジ卜だ
It's their base.
頼む
Please.
I'll go and talk to Rufus.
俺はルーファウスと話してくる
逃げないで！
Don't run away!
わかるよ
I understand.
こどもたちをみつけても
何もできないかもしれない
Even if you find the children, you may not be able to do anything.
Maybe something will happen that can never be undone.
もしかしたら また 取り返しの
つかないことになるかも
それが怖しいんでしょ ?
That's what you're afraid of, right?
でも もっと今を
いろんなことを受け止めてよ
But you need to accept what's going on right now!
重い? だって仕方ないよ
重いんだから
Is it hard? Well, of course it's going to be hard.
Unless you're planning to live
the rest of your life like this, you'll just have to deal with it.
ひとりで生きていける人以外は
我慢しなくちゃ
You don't like being alone, do you?
ひとり ぼっちはやなんでしょ？
You don't answer the phone, but you won't throw it away either, do you?
出ないくせに電話は手放さないもんね
アジ卜 おまえがいけよ　と
Their base. Go there, dude.
私たち 思い出に負けたの?
Have we...
...lost to our memories?
だって 見殺しにしたんだぞ ?
You see... I let you die.
You just keep dragging along, don't you?
ホント　ズルズルズルズル！
ねえ
Hey.
もう許してあげたら ?
Can't you just forgive yourself?
Can sins be forgiven?
罪って 許されるのか?
・・・試したことはない
I've never tried.
Try?
試す?
Try...
試す・・・
マリン　帰るぞ
Marlene, let's go home.
やってみるよ
I will try.
結果は連絡する
I'll let you know how it goes.
わたしリーブです"
お仕事はどうですか?
It's me, Reeve. How's your work going?
チラシ見ましたけど あんなので
商売になるんですか?
I saw your flyer. Do you really think you can make money off of that?
That sounds like you though, Cloud-san.
クラウドさんらしいですけどね
良ければお手伝いしたい・・・
If you don't mind, I'd like to help. I'll call you again.
ヒーリンにいるレノから電話あったよ
仕事の依頼だって
He's requesting you for a job.
Hey, it's Yuffie-chan! It's been a while!
ひさしぶり　ユフィちゃんだよ
あのさ ウ一夕イから子供たちがいなくなっちゃったんだけど
I've got my claim staked out, so I'll be heading to see Marlene soon!
I just wanted to tell you that all the children in Wutai disappeared.
何か知ってる? 情報ちよ一だ仁丶!
お願いだよ
Do you know anything about it? Give me a call. Please.
He sounded kind of strange.
なんだか様子が変だったけど・・・
気をつけてね
Be careful, okay?
I've never blamed you for what happened.
悪く思ったこと 一度もないよ
You came, didn't you? That was enough.
来てくれたでしよ?
それだけでじゅうぶんん
Hey, are you listening?
おい！ 聞いてるのか
Why the hell are you doing this?
何でこんなまねするんだ
デンゼル！
Denzel!
Denzel?
デンゼル！
Denzel!
What are you doing?
何してるんだ ?
Mother is here, isn't she?
母さんはここなんだろ?
どうして?
Why do you think so?
この・・・なんだ? 記念碑?
作ったのは神羅だ
This... What is it?
Monument?
Shinra made it, right?
だからここに隠したってか?
So that's why you think it's here?
ちがう？
Are we wrong?
Dunno.
さあな
俺たちも聞いてないぞ　と
We never heard a word about it either, dude!
See? I knew they were hiding it somewhere.
ほら やっぱりどこかに
隠しているんだ
ルー ド なんとか言ってやれ!
R-Rude, say something!
うぉりゃー！
痛い?
Does it hurt?
うん
Yeah.
でも デンゼルほどじゃない
Still, it's nothing compared to Denzel's pain.
治るの ?
Will he get better?
分からない
I don't know.
デンゼルのために 治す方法
あんなに探していたのにね
But... you looked so hard for a way to make him better!
So you knew?
知っていたのか
クラウド 机の上 片付けないからね
Yep! Because Cloud never cleaned off his desk!
Right, I didn't...
そうだな
ねえ クラウドはー
Hey, Cloud...
デンゼルの星痕が消せないから
おうちから出て行ったの？
Did you leave home because Denzel wasn't getting better?
Or because you got sick, too?
自分にも星痕カが出たから ?
俺はー
I...
自分ひとり守れない
...couldn't even protect myself.
そう思ったからかな
I suppose that's the reason.
"How could someone who can't protect himself protect his family?!"
自分ひとり守れない奴に
家族なんか守れるが! !
・・・って 父ちゃんが言ってたよ
...is what Dad always said.
クラウド あきらめないで
Cloud, don't give up!
マリンとデンゼルとティファ
Marlene, Denzel, Tifa...
You guys are always rescuing me.
いつも俺を助けてくれたよな
俺はずっ と誰かに守られてきた
I've been protected this entire time.
今度は俺の番だな
It's about time... for me to return the favor.
うん
Yeah!
So, Kadaj...
なあ 力ダ一ジュ
ひとつ 教えてくれ
Tell me one thing.
ひとつだけだよ
Just one thing.
おまえは ジェノバ細胞を手に入れて
元通りになると言っていたが・・・
You said that you'll return to the way you were, once you have Jenova's Cells.
What do you mean by that?
あれはどういう意味だ？
かれが・・・帰ってくる
He is...
...coming back.
・ ・ ・セフィ囗ス
Sephiroth...
悪夢だな
The nightmare.
Seems like it.
らしいね
Seems?
らしい?
僕はセフィ囗スを知らない
I don't know who Sephiroth is.
ああ 感じているだけだ
Yeah... I can only sense him.
It pisses me off.
イライラするよ
母さんは僕とセフィ囗ス
どっちを・ ・・
I wonder which one Mother prefers, Sephiroth or me?
哀れ 思念体
Pitiful Remnant.
どっちだろうとあんたたちの結末は同じだ!
Either way, you'll all end up the same way!
Mother arrived on this planet after a long journey.
母さんLま長い旅をして
この星にやって来た
愚かな連中を宇宙から
消し去るためにね
In order to wipe out all you idiots from this universe.
でも　わかるよねえ？
But... you understand, don't you?
ここは母さんカが来た頃と
何も変わっちゃいない
Nothing has changed here since Mother arrived.
だから僕が母さんを喜ばせてあげるんだ
That's why I want to make Mother happy.
I'll do anything Mother asks me to.
母さんが命じるなら何でもやるよ
ふん 悪夢再びか
The nightmare all over again, eh?
あんたたちがいる限り
何度でも同じことが起こるのさ
As long as you people exist, the same thing will occur over and over.
・・・星を巡るライフストリームに
The Lifestream that encircles the planet...
Going back and forth between the worlds of life and death.
生と死の間(はざま）を行きつ戻りつ
その繰り退しこそが命の正体ならば
If that never-ending circle is life,
歴史が繰り退されるのは必然
then it is inevitable that history should repeat.
ジェノバだかセフィロスか
知らないが
I don't care if it's Jenova or Sephiroth.
何度でも事を起こすがいい
Let it happen as many times as it wants.
我々は命のさだめに従い
We will follow our destiny,
そのたびに おまえたちを
阻止してみせる
and that's why we will always try to stop you.
President, is that your excuse for taking Mother away?
社長・ ・ ・
それLま母さんを横取りした言い訳 ?
Are you maybe feeling remorse?
本当は後悔してるんじゃない？
後悔? 私は・ ・ ・楽しくて仕方がない
Remorse?
I'm enjoying this a great deal.
That's good.
よかった　じゃあそろそろ
終わりにしようか
Well then, it's time to put an end to this.
デンゼル　逃げるわよ！
Denzel, let's run for it.
うぉりゃー！
This is...
こぉりゃ
無理だ・・・
...impossible.
Is it coming?
来てるか ! ?
見たくない
I don't want to look!
楽しいなあ　おい
Isn't this fun, guys?
Not at all, dude.
全然だぞ と
You guys sure are persistent!
おまえら しつこいぞ　と
だから・・・母さんを返してくれたら
それでおしまいなんだけどな
Like I said, if you guys give us back Mother, it will all be over.
おまえら・・・
You guys...
What do you need Jenova's head for?
ジェノバの首 どうするつもりだ?
リ ユ二オンだのなんだの正気かよ
That "reunion" crap... Are you guys serious?
俺たちは母さんに会いただけだ
We just want to see our mother.
母さんがな これからのこと
全部決めてくれるんだ
Mother will decide everything from now on.
Well, where is Mother?
で 母さんは?
Mother this, Mother that. It's only Jenova's head.
母さん母さんって・・・
ジェノバの首じゃねえか
Hey!
おい！
Don't talk about Mother like that.
母さんをそんなふう[に呼ぶな
You won't be forgiven!
許さねえ
・・・わるかった
Sorry about that.
Yeah...
そうだな・・・って なんで謝るんだ !
Why the hell are we apologizing?
Tifa?
ティファ？
Why you...
このやろう !
You stay there and protect your mother.
ここで母ちゃんを守れ
Barret!
バレット！
Marlene is safe, right?
マリンは無事なんだろうな! ? えっ?
かなわんなー
No match!
うつぷ
Who's using my Materia?
ア夕シのマテリア使ってるの 誰 ?
Obviously, the bad guys.
もちろん 悪者
Damn!
くっそー
Who's she?
誰？
Brand new airship! The "Shera"!
新型だ一 ! シ工ラ号
I'll give you guys a ride later!
あとで乗せてやるからな !
電話屋はどこだ・ ・・
Where's the phone shop?
あの人は ?
Who's he?
みんな 仲間だよ
They're all friends.
デンゼル 店まで走れる?
Denzel, think you can run all the way back to the shop?
うん
Sure!
しつこい！
Give it a rest!
Tifa!
ティファ！!
デンゼル！
Denzel!
Cloud!
クラウド!
遅くなってすまなかった
Sorry for being late.
No, it's fine.
ううん　いいんだよ
大丈夫 ?
Are you okay?
うん
Yeah.
Marlene is fine. I left her at the shop.
マリンは無事だ 店に置いてきた
Okay.
うん
軽くなった気がする
I feel lighter.
ん?
Huh?
引きずりすき'て すり減ったかな
I kept dragging my burden along, so maybe it's worn down some.
俺 ひとりで店へ帰るよ
I'm going back to the shop alone.
マリンと待ってる
I'll be waiting with Marlene.
Cloud, you'll come back too, right?
クラウドも帰って来るよな？
うん
負けるもんか !
I can't give up here!
おせえんだよ !
You're late!
This is fun, President!
楽しいな 社長 次は何を呼ぶ ?
What should I summon next?
母さん?
Mother!
You didn't sense her? What an awful son you are.
気づけよ 親不孝者
行け クラウド!
Go, Cloud!
ほらよ !
Here you go!
はいなー！
ぬお~
Fly!
飛ベ!
まだまだ !
Not yet!
Here.
はい！
Mother!
母さん !
社長!
President!
相手 間違えてんじゃいぞ　と
Don't forget about me, dude!
パパーン！パパパパーン！
Bam! Ba-ba-ba-ba-bam!
ルード!
Rude!
ア"~! ?
Oh man, oh man, oh man...
ヤバいヤバい　ヤバいぞ　と
お一 ル一ド 無事だったか!
Oh, Rude... You're safe!
いや・・・ そうでもない
Nope. Not at all.
せんぱーい！
Senpai!
Yo, partner.
よう 相棒
Is this...
これ 強力なのか?
...powerful?
神羅の技術を結集した
The culmination of Shinra technology.
あんたが作ったのか・・・
You made this?
威力はともかく 派手だ
Putting aside its power, it's rather flashy.
おっと
Whoa now.
You like it, don't you, partner?
好きだろ 相棒?
No overtime today, dude.
今日は残業ナシだぞ と
母さん・・・
Mother!
Mother...
母さん !
行こう クラウド
Let's go, Cloud.
I've finally found my mother.
僕 やっと母さんに会えたんだ
何が始まるんだ?
What's going to happen next?
Mother will tell me.
母さんが教えてくれるさ
Remnants know nothing, huh?
・・・思念体は何も知らないか
どうせ僕は操り人形・・・
I'm just a puppet, after all.
Just like...
昔のあんたと
...you used to be!
同じだ!
Cloud, I brought Materia for you.
クラウ ド マテ'リア持って来たよ!
Don't shake it!
揺らすな !
Hey, Cid, hurry up and land.
おい シド! 早く降ろせ!
Shut up! Just jump. Jump!
うるせえ ! ジャンプしろ　ジャンプ!
ひとりで戦わせてやれ
Let him fight alone.
Huh?!
はあ!?
あいつはセフィ囗スの思念体・・・
That guy is Sephiroth's Remnant.
He's like a larva, so to speak.
いわば幼虫のようなものだ
A larva?! A bug? He's a bug?!
幼虫? 虫? 虫なの~?
Missy, please be quiet.
お嬢さん 黙っとき
いつか せフィ囗スになるってか
So he'll eventually become Sephiroth, right?
Hey, does Cloud know about this?
ねえ クラウドは それ 知ってるのかな?
Most likely.
おそらく
I see.
そっか・ ・ ・
Let's leave him alone.
ひとりにしてあげよう
I don't get it. Explain it to me!
わからないよ 説明してよ !
オ卜コの話だ
It's a man thing.
Sexual discrimination, discrimination!
差別！さべーつ！
Missy, quiet down!
お嬢さん 黙っとき !
オトコもわかんねえって
Some men don't understand either.
Two years ago...
2年前・・・
We had such a strong will in the final battle.
最後の戦いの時には
確かにあったはずの強い気持ち
It's only been two years, but somehow that strength has slipped away.
たった2年なのに　いつのまにか
無くしてしまったあの気持ち
I think Cloud has found it again.
それをクラウ ドは取り戻したんだと思う
チッ・・・。１０分待ってやる
I'll wait for 10 minutes.
Cloud is a pain in the ass, as ever.
相変わらずジャンプんだねえ
クラウドは
He's just straightforward.
正直なの
僕のリユ二オン 見せてあげるよ
I'll show you my Reunion.
久しぶりだな クラウド
It's been a long time, Cloud.
Your Geostigma is gone?
星痕をなくしたのか?
残念だ
What a shame.
Just what are you after?
いったい 何カが望みなんだ?
The ghosts of Geostigma victims...
星痕を宿した死者の思念
...flow in the Lifestream around the planet,
それはライフス卜リ一ムとともに
星を巡り
and will eventually devour it.
やがて星を侵食する・ ・ ・
What I want, Cloud...
私の望みはな クラウド
...is to sail the darkness of the universe with this planet as my vessel...
この星を船として
宇宙の闇を旅することだ
...just as my mother did long ago.
カつて母がそうしたようにな
We will find a new planet eventually,
やがて我らは新しい星を見いだ し
and construct a shining future there.
その地で輝げる未来を創造する
この星はどうなる?
And what will happen to this planet?
Who knows? That's up to you.
さあ・ ・ ・おまえ次第だな
おねえちゃん?
Miss?
ほう 何がおまえを強く した ?
What has made you so strong?
あんたには言いたくないね
I don't feel like telling you!
おまえヘの贈り物を考えていた・・・
I was thinking of a parting gift for you.
絶望を贈ろうか？
Shall I give you despair?
Kneel down and show me how you look when you're begging for mercy.
跪（ひざまず）き 許しを請う姿を見せてくれ
Do you remember the pain you once tasted, Cloud?
あの時の痛みを憶えている? クラウド
今再び 忘れられぬ痛みを刻もう
Allow me to give you yet another taste of that unforgettable agony!
おまえの最も大切なものは ?
What is the most important thing to you?
Will you grant me the pleasure of taking it away?
それを奪う喜びをくれないか?
俺ならまだあきらめないぜ
If it were me, I wouldn't be throwing in the towel yet!
No matter how hopeless the situation seemed.
たとえ絶望的な状況でもな
Embrace your dreams!
夢を抱きしめろ
そして どんな時でも
ソルジヤーの誇りは手放すな
And... never, ever let go of your pride as a SOLDIER.
ま ソルジャーにはならなかったープど
ハー卜の間題だ ハ一卜の
Well, you never really managed to become a SOLDIER.
But it's a matter of heart, anyway!
Zack...
ザ'ックス・・・
Need me to lend a hand?
手・ ・・ 貸してほしいか?
I mean, you kicked his ass once, right?
一度 倒れした相手だろ
楽勝じゃない
It's a piece of cake!
Right.
ああ・・・
もう・・・ 忘れるなよ
Don't you ever forget again...
...that I'm the proof you once existed.
俺が おまえの生きた証だ
So pathetic.
・・・哀れだな
あんたは何もわかっていない
You understand nothing.
大切じやないものなんかない
There is nothing that isn't important to me.
Rest quietly...
思い出の中でじっとしていてくれ
...as a memory.
私は・・・
I...
...will not become a memory.
思い出にはならないさ
兄さん・・・
Brother...
Kadaj...
カダ一ジュ ?
Huh?
え？
You can stop trying so hard, okay?
もう　頑張るの やめよう?
Is that you, Mother?
母さん・・・なの?
みんなのところ 帰ろう?
Let's go back to everyone, okay?
うん
Okay.
やったー どんなもんだい!
All right! That's how you do it!
な 言った通りだろ!
See, just like I said.
Yes, Cloud-san is the man!
男やー クラウドさんは男や !
やれば出来るんだから クラウドは
Cloud can do anything if he tries.
Hold on tight, you guys!
お前ら ちゃんとつかまってる
You were always with us, weren't you?
ずっと　いてくれたんだよね
ありがとう
Thank you.
一緒に帰ろう
Let's go back together.
みんなで遊ほ'う
Let's all play... together.
クラウド!
Cloud!
Cloud will come back too, won't he?
・・・クラウ ドも帰ってくるよな
Let's go!
行こう
Okay!
うん
Mother?
母さん・・・?
また!
Again?
何度目かな 母さんって呼ばれたの
Why does everyone keep calling Mother?
いいじやないの 慕われて
Who cares? It means you're loved.
こんな大きな子　いりません
I don't want such a big kid.
残念 おまえの居場所
ここにはないってよ
Too bad...
She's saying there's no place for you here.
The lady told us...
お姉ちゃんがね
...that you'd come here.
クラウドがここにくるからって
おかえりなさい
Welcome home.
ただいま
I'm back.
まだ星痕が麦消ない子もいるんだ
There are still children who have Geostigma.
Yeah.
ああ
さあ 治してもらうのよ
Come on. Let's get you cured.
It's fine now.
もう 大丈夫
頑張つて
Be strong.
All right, let's all jump in and celebrate!
さあ じゃんじゃん飛び込め
It worked! It worked!
治った 治った
It doesn't hurt anymore!
Wow.
That's amazing water!
You're really cured!
もう 大丈夫 だね
Everything's fine now, right?
うん
Yeah.
俺は・・・
I'm...
...not alone.
ひとりじゃない
Is that someone's grave?
No...
It's where a hero's journey once began.